hey everyone welcome back to the Tosca
automation playlist and we are talking
about the top 10 Tosca best practices
now we are in the last two best
practices we have already spoken about
eight best practices so if you have not
watched them please go ahead and watch
all of these before we continue with
this particular best practice also you
might want to subscribe to our Channel
if you have not already done it so that
you don't miss out on the upcoming
videos
now talking about this particular best
practice
so try centers recommends that you
should set the proper work states for
your test cases
now what are the different levels of
this workstates and where this work
state is present I would show you with
an example but setting the work states
on test cases does provide a good
overview on the overall status of this
test case now what do you mean by the
overall status is whether the test case
is under review whether the test case is
um you're working on it currently or you
are planning that particular test case
or you have completed the test case
right so this particular setting is very
important when you are working within a
team because there may be scenarios
where you would be working on the same
test case or at least under the same
folder with your other teammates so it's
very important for each of the teammates
to know uh what level of completion is
done for that particular test case Okay
so looking at the test case you can find
out whether the test case is still in
progress or it is completed or it is
still in the planning stages right
so that helps you to plan your work much
better and also it provides a good
overview for the management on what is
the status of the work with the team
right
also it helps with the overview of the
requirements section because the
requirements are linked to the test case
so depending on the work state of a test
case the requirement uh overall coverage
and the execution status changes in the
requirements section and this
requirements section is the main
dashboard for the test management team
or even the stakeholders right so if you
are not setting the proper work state
for your test cases then um the
requirement coverage may not be showing
correctly for the team management and
that will create problems okay so let's
see with an example of what is this work
state how you can set this in a test
case and how this is linked to the
requirement section okay
so coming back to Tosca I can open any
particular test case okay no matter
which test case you work on uh there is
a column called work state now if you
cannot see this column you can always go
to column Chooser and then just select
that particular work state column okay
and then it will be appearing here
now this work state has three status
okay
uh the first is planned the second is in
work and the third is completed
so whenever you are starting with your
uh particular test case it will be in
the plant Stitch okay at this stage you
are trying to go through the scenarios
and you are planning how you can build
this particular test case okay so you
can keep this in the plant stage once
you start working on the test case you
can change it to in work and once you
have completed the test case you can
change it to completed okay so these are
the three work states it's pretty simple
so it's basically the status of the
current test case which you are
currently working on and the right work
state can help you and your teammates
and even the team management okay
so that's how you can set a particular
work state and the three different work
states which you can set for a
particular test case right and you will
see uh for every uh test case a work
state is always set right
now how this is linked to the
requirements okay so if I go back to uh
the requirement section here you can see
that we have got different requirements
and under this we have got this
particular test case which is linked to
this requirement okay
so our coverage specified is 100 our
execution state is 97 percent
now if I jump to the linked test case
okay
so this is the particular test case okay
which is present in that requirement or
linked to that particular requirement
now this work state is currently
completed
but what if I change it to in work okay
so either I forgot to make it completed
or I am still working on this particular
test case right so I make it uh in work
and now if I go back to requirements you
will see the coverage specified has
decreased from 100 percent to 69 percent
for this particular requirement and the
execution state has also reduced to 65
percent
so that's the impact it has on your
overall requirement coverage and also
the execution percentage because this
particular test case may have a certain
number of weight right you can see here
the contribution is quite High For This
Test case it is 54.77 percent so it's a
very important test case uh in terms of
this particular requirement and that is
why it has got a higher weightage and
also the contribution is much higher in
terms of the coverage and so as soon as
I change uh my test case to in work my
requirements coverage gets affected also
the execution state gets affected okay
so if you forget or if you don't update
your test case in the right manner then
your requirements are going to get
screwed and that is going to uh
provide a different picture to the test
management team on how much the coverage
is or the execution state is okay so
it's very important as you can see to
set the right work state
okay so once I set it to completed and
then I go back here now the coverage
specified is 100 and the execution is
also higher right
so that's the impact it has if you don't
set the correct work state for your test
cases and that's why it is one of the
most important uh best practices which
you should follow whenever you are
working in a team or you have got the
requirements linked to your test cases
so that's all for this particular video
I hope you enjoyed it and you learned
something new today uh there are lots
more videos coming up so keep watching
so until we speak again keep watching
and keep learning Tosca